G. D. Hsiung papers
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Research materials, Series XI
  - Experiments, 1956-1997; Subseries 2
    - 2'-nor-cGMP/DHPG Combination Study: Experiments III, IV, and V, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - 2'-nor-cGMP/DHPG Combination Study: Summary/Publications, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - DHPG/AZT Combination Study: Part 1, 1991-1992 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      Antiviral study of DHPG and AZT on guinea pigs, in vivo and in vitro. Submitted Article: "Zidovudine Antagonizes the Antiviral Effects Against CMV Infection in Cultured Cells and in Guinea Pigs," 1992. Presentation: "Combined Antiviral Effect and Cytotoxicity of Ganciclovir and Azidothymidine against CMV Infection in Cultured Cells," New Orleans, 1991.
    - DHPG/AZT Combination Study: Part II, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - HCMV-HIV Interaction: Introduction, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 7)
      From folder labeled "HCMV-HIV-Interaction", these files contain primary data, correspondence, protocols and electron microscopy for a study done on HCMV and HIV. Miriam Margalith and Martin Hirsch were involved as investigators.
    - HCMV-HIV Interaction: Part I to Part III, 1990 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - HCMV-HIV Interaction: Correspondence and Primary Data, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - HCMV-HIV Interaction: Experiment VIII, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - HCMV-HIV Interaction: Experiment X, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - HCMV-HIV Interaction: Electron Micrographs, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - HCMV-HIV Interaction: HCMV/HEF Virus Control Electron Micrographs, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - HCMV-HIV Interaction: Light Microscopy Day 7-21, 1991 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Dolphin Cell Cultures, 1991-1993 (Box 46, Folder 15)
      Collaboration with Charles Buck and Daniel Medina.
    - Virus Isolate 176: Correspondence 1992, 1992-1994 (Box 46, Folder 16)
      Collaboration with Charles Buck: virus identification and isolation for a culture taken from female orca whale. Additional discussion of herpesvirus in marine animals, including seals and dolphins.
    - Virus Isolate 176: Correspondence 1993, 1992-1994 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Virus Isolate 176: Correspondence 1994, 1992-1994 (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Virus Isolate 176: Electron Micrographs/Slides, 1992-1994 (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - Virus Isolate 176: Background Citations, 1992-1994 (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Hepatitis C Virus Liver Biopsy, 1994-1997 (Box 46, Folder 21)
      From a file labeled "Liver Biopsy-Tainan", this early example of Hepatitis C Virus studies contains electron micrographs of a liver biopsy from Caroline Fong and Daniel Medina as well as two hepatitis C conference pamphlets from 1997.
  - Data Record Books and Laboratory Log Books, Subseries 3
    - Laboratory notebooks (19) on Guinea Pig Herpes-Like Virus (GPHLV), 1979-1988 (Box 47)
      Nineteen bound laboratory notebooks on lymphocyte transformation by Guinea Pig Herpes-Like Virus (GPHLV), with transformation assays; antiviral studies of the effect of acyclovir on guinea pig herpes-like virus; and many other studies in vitro and in vivo. Authors of the laboratory notebooks from G. D, Hsiung's laboratory in the VA include Jane Armstrong, Kenneth Dowler, Zoltan Nagy, and Thomas Brady.
    - Laboratory notebooks (13) on Guinea Pig CMV, HIV, and AZT, 1988-1991 (Box 48)
      Bound laboratory notebooks from G. D. Hsiung's laboratory in the VA on Guinea Pig CMV, HIV, and AZT, the first successful drug against AIDS. The notebooks also examine other antiviral agents against HIV. Authors of the notebooks include Juesen Feng, Zhihua Yang, M. Tung, Robin Emrick, and Pei Yu Tian. One notebook contains studies on Yale researcher Dr. William Prusoff's compounds.
    - Laboratory log books (20) on the running of the Virology Laboratory (Box 49)
      Includes records of photographic data, use of microscopes; record of isotopes sent to the VA Virology Laboratory; logbook of drugs received for an NIH contract including correspondence tipped in; record of animals; logbook of new drugs; journal subscriptions of the laboratory; records of Hsiung's "entertainment" expenses, her costs of attendance at scientific meetings, and her dues for professional societies.
  - Additional Research Materials, Subseries 4
    - Viruses Submitted to the American Type Culture Collection (ATCC), 1963-1968 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      Viruses Dr. Hsiung submitted to the American Type Culture Collection, primarily DA5 and SV40.
    - ATCC Virus Inventory, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 2)
      Correspondence of the Viral and Rickettsial Registry and Distribution Center of the ATCC with Hsiung, and inventory of virus specimens in the registry, 1963.
    - Research with ATCC: Chromosome Study of DA and SV40, 1963 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Research with ATCC: SV40 Virus Comparison, 1994 (Box 50, Folder 4)
      Part of a collaboration with Charles Buck. Includes electron micrographs of SV40
    - Memoranda of Sending/Receiving Cell Cultures, 1989-1991 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Ideas for Research, 1970-1990 (Box 50, Folder 6)
      Materials together as found. Heterogeneous notes for research topics. Includes an undated map of the offices in the Virology Laboratory.
    - BW 1117/ BW 767 Anti-Viral Study GPCMV and GPHLV funded by Burroughs-Wellcome, 1984-1987 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      Includes correspondence and some data.
    - Antiviral study BW1117, 1985 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      Primary data and data reduction for antiviral study BW1117 for Burroughs Wellcome. With Jane Armstrong and Zoltan Nagy.
    - Proposal to Pfizer on evaluation of an anti-viral compound, 1981 (Box 50, Folder 9)
      Proposal includes basic procedures for testing drugs in the guinea pig model with genital herpes, and "The Effect of Phosphonoformate on Genital Herpes in Guinea Pigs."
    - Photomicrographs of CPE and plaques in bottle cultures, 1960s (Box 50, Folder 10)
      The first three folders contain photomicrograaphs of Virus isolation of various viruses: arbovirus, herpes, polio. Photographs, found together in a box, are glued to card stock and are sometimes labeled.
    - Photomicrographs of CPE and plaques in bottle cultures, 1960s (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Photomicrographs of CPE and plaques in bottle cultures, 1960s (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - "Parainfluenza 5": Isolation, Properties, Serology (1), 1957-1967 (Box 51, Folder 1)
      Very early studies on the DA virus including primary data and bottle cultures. Compares DA with SV5 and SA. This and the next folder were removed from a ring notebook.
    - "Parainfluenza 5": Isolation, Properties, Serology (2), 1957-1967 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Isolation of DA Virus (1), 1962 (Box 51, Folder 3)
      This and the next two folders were removed from a notebook labelled "DA Hemadsorption Para 1 and Non Sp." Consists of small photographs attached to paper backing.
    - Isolation of DA Virus (2), 1962 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Isolation of DA Virus (3) (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - "TA Virus", 1967-1968 (Box 51, Folder 6)
      Rhesus monkey kidney, origin of TA virus.
    - Chronic Bronchitis and Emphysema - clinical project with Dr. Robert Green (Restricted), 1968 (Box 51, Folder 7)
      Robert Green was an infectious diseases clinician. The material contains patient names.
    - Photomicrographs: Original isolation of GPHLV, 1969 February 14 (Hsiung and Kaplow), 1969-1970 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - "Organ Cultures" (1), 1971-1972 (Box 51, Folder 9)
      Data on antiviral study of GPHLV in vivo (rabbits, LA229), and isolation of viruses from various organs in various animals. This and the next folder were removed from a ring notebook.
    - "Organ Cultures" (2), 1971-1972 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Guinea Pig C - C-type Virus Particles (1), 1971-1972 (Box 52, Folder 1)
      This and the next two folders were removed from a notebook labelled "Guinea Pig C." Contains photomicrographs of cancer-causing viruses and leukemic cells.
    - Guinea Pig C - C-type Virus Particles (2), 1971-1972 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Guinea Pig C - C-type Virus Particles (3), 1971-1972 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Guinea Pig Leukemia (1), 1971-1974 (Box 52, Folder 4)
      Electron micrographs of C-type leukemia in guinea pigs, important for oncology of viruses in animals, BUDR treatments.
    - Guinea Pig Leukemia (2), 1971-1975 (Box 52, Folder 5)
      Also contains reprints on the isolation of DA virus.
    - Electron micrographs of embryo budding herpesvirus, 1974 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      With correspondence with M. A. Epstein, Department of Pathology, University of Bristol.
    - Antiviral FMAU - Guinea Pig Lymphotropic Herpes (1), 1974-1984 (Box 52, Folder 7)
      This and the next folder were removed from a ring binder. Primary data and some reduced data.
    - Antiviral FMAU - Guinea Pig Lymphotropic Herpes (2), 1974-1984 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Photos and charts, probably for classes (1), ca. 1977 (Box 52, Folder 9)
      This and the next two folders contain mounted images that Dr. Booss thought Hsiung might have used in teaching. These were removed from a box. They include images of tissue cultures, photomicrographs, serological assays, diagrams of apparatus, and in vivo experiments.
    - Photos and charts, probably for classes (2), ca. 1977 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Photos and charts, probably for classes (3), ca. 1977 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Photographs - Genital Herpes, ca. 1982-1984 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Photographs -- Guinea Pig Genital Herpes Latency (1), 1984 (Box 53, Folder 2)
      This and the following folder were removed from a notebook. Guinea pig model for vaginal herpes, images of cell culture, tissue culture, organ specimens, simplex model.
    - Photographs -- Guinea Pig Genital Herpes Latency (2), 1984 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Photomicrographs - New Jersey Study, Michalski Experiment 1, 1987 August 5 (Box 53, Folder 4)
      Hsiung's collaboration with Frank J. Michalski, Ph.D., Virology Laboratory, Meth Path, Teterboro, New Jersey.
    - Photomicrographs - Michalski Experiment 2, 1987 August 24 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence on collaboration with Frank Michalski, Belinda Yen-Lieberman, and Mark Liu, 1987-1988 (Box 53, Folder 6)
      This relates to a "collaboration on studies of clinical specimens of obtained from patients possibly infected with HIV." There are no patient names. Mark Liu was associated with Johns Hopkins University and the Pulmonary Division, Francis Scott Key Medical Center, Baltimore. Belinda Yen-Lieberman was at the Cleveland Clinic Foundation. Folder includes data and images exchanged.
    - "AIDS Virus Morphology" - Morphogenesis of HIV in H9 Cells, ca. 1987 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - HIV Morphology H9, ca. 1987 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - HIV B-G H9 "Fixed in paraformald." (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - HIV CHU-5 Day 7, 1988 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      The photomicrographs in this and the following folders, related to HIV and AZT, are labeled according to experiment number.
    - HIV Experiment, Dr. Yang, Day 10, 1988 April (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - HIV Experiment Dr. Yang CHU-5 AZT-HMBBAU, Day 14, 1988 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - HIV CHU-6 Day 7, 1988 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - HIV CHU-6 Day 10, 1988 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - HIV CHU-6 AZT and HMBBAU (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - HIV CHU-7 Day 7 Low Power Fields, 1988 July 29 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - HIV CHU-7 Day 7, 1988 July (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - HIV CHU-8, 1988 August (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - HIV CHU-8 Day 7, 1988 September (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - HIV CHU-8 Day 10, 1988 September (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - GPE-GPHLV "164" Antiviral Study (1), 1988-1989 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - GPE-GPHLV "164" Antiviral Study (2), 1988-1989 (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Parainfluenza 2 3 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Influenza A, 1992 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - HLV In Vivo Experiments (1), 1992-1994 (Box 54, Folder 13)
      Work done with Ken Dowler. This and the next folder were removed from a 3-ring notebook. Contains hematological data for HLV, primary and reduced data.
    - HLV In Vivo Experiments (2), 1992-1994 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Original observation of SV40, 1957 (Box 55, Folder 1)
      Photograph of Dr. Hsiung's original image of the SV40 virus, working with Dr. Gaylord, 1957.
    - Diagnostic virology reagents and techniques (1), 1960s (Box 55, Folder 2)
      This and the following folder were removed from a 3-ring binder. Among the techniques represented is the fluorescent antibody technique.
    - Diagnostic virology reagents and techniques (2), 1960s (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Electromicrographs used for an EM course, 1968 (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - BEEM Capsule Technique for Electromicroscopy, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 5)
      Folder contains very high resolution images taken with this technique.
    - Collaboration with Dr. Todaro, NCI-NIH, 1975 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      Folder contains hand-written notes on a proposed collaboration with Dr. Todaro on guinea pig oncornavirus.
    - Techniques for evaluating antiviral agents with cell culture, 1988 April (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Photomicrographs: Cell cultures - CPE (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Electromicrographs: Guinea-pig herpes-like virus and guinea pig retrovirus (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Antiviral experiments: Herpes simplex type 1 and 2, antiviral treatment in cell culture (Box 55, Folder 10)
      Folder contains photos of diagrams and graphs.
    - Additional images (1) (Box 55, Folder 11)
      These were considered to be important or representative by Dr. John Booss.
    - Additional images (2) (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Slides and other images of GPHLV used for teaching (1) (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Slides and other images of GPHLV used for teaching (2) (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Slides and other images of GPHLV used for teaching (3) (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - Slides of various kinds of viruses, used for teaching (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - Laboratory projects and programs, 1975-1978 (Box 56, Folder 1)
      Many of the folders in this box were in Hsiung's category "References." The category otherwise contained mostly photocopies of articles by others that were discarded. This folder contains lists of who was working on what in the laboratory.
    - Requests for drugs and chemicals to test, 1969-1973 (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - Cell culture in vitro: Comparison of immunohistology, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Various comparisons of viruses: tables and notes (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Chart of types of assays to locate a virus (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Notes on genital herpes (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - Notes on cytomegalovirus (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Notes on animal care in the laboratory (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Talk and slides on Epstein-Barr virus (Box 56, Folder 9)
      Talk may be by Stanley McCormick. 38 slides developed locally in Hamden, Connecticut, and probably from Dr. Hsiung's laboratory.